Finding Aid for Frank O. Johnson papers, 1913-1950
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank O. Johnson papers 1913-1950
Johnson, Frank O., 1877-1950.
1 linear foot
851580 Aa 2
Great Lakes ship captain; correspondence, logbooks, payroll books, and a scrapbook.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Helen Dennison (donor no. 5254 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Frank O. Johnson was a Great Lakes working for the Morton Salt Company aboard the S.S. Covalt. He was from Ludington, Michigan.
The collection includes correspondence, reminiscences, and scrapbook of clippings largely concerning Great Lakes shipping, particularly Johnson's work for the Morton Salt Company. Logbooks, cashbook, and time and payroll books detail the operation of the Steamer Covalt. There are also a few photographs.
Subjects:
Business records.; Covalt (Ship); Great Lakes (North America); Johnson, Frank O., 1877-1950.; Ludington (Mich.); Morton Salt Company.; Shipping--Great Lakes (North America).
Subjects - Visual Materials:
City of Flint (Ship); Ferries.; H.C. Akeley (Ship); Johnson, Frank O., 1877-1950.; Marine accidents.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Personal and professional papers
  - Correspondence, 1942-1950 (Box 1)
  - Reminiscences, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1913-1949 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 1)
  - S.S. Covalt time and payroll book, 1922-1926 (Box 1)
  - S.S. Covalt time and payroll book, 1926-1935 (Box 1)
  - S.S. Covalt timebook, 1926 and 1935-1942 (Box 1)
  - S.S. Craigsmen cashbook, 1922-1927; also S.S. Covalt cashbook, 1929-1942 (Box 1)
  - Logbook, 1929-1942 (Box 1)
  - Logbook, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
  - Steamer Marion time and payroll book, 1919-1921 (Box 1)
  - Payroll book, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Photographs: photos of Johnson and of ships, 2 envelopes (Box 1)